<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infrastructure on Locke Data Talks</title>
    <link>http://lockelife.com/talks/tags/infrastructure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Infrastructure on Locke Data Talks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lockelife.com/talks/tags/infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coping with x2,000 data volumes growth</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/coping-with-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/coping-with-growth/</guid>
      <description>Experience my pain as I try to build an Azure Data Platform that scales.
Abstract I worked in a startup and our volumes started small, really small. I was the data scientist but I needed to actually build a data platform first. By the end of 6 months, daily volumes were 2,000 times the size. This talk takes you through my 6 months of learning how to build a high-scale data platform whilst requirements, scale, and technology were all changing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R &amp; SQL Server for real-time predictions</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/r-and-sql-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/r-and-sql-server/</guid>
      <description>Putting data science models with SQL Server can be a great and simple way to operationalise your data science models. Learn how to do it.
Abstract Embedding your R (and soon Python!) models in SQL Server enables you to add predictive capabilities to your applications and analytics in place of buying expensive components or making substantial changes to your systems. In this demo-packed talk, you&amp;rsquo;ll see how you can go from a model built in R to making predictions on the fly in SQL Server 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data &#43; Docker = Discombobulating?</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/data-docker-discombobulating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/data-docker-discombobulating/</guid>
      <description>Learn about Docker and how you can store data in Docker containers safely.
Abstract If you’re like me, you like your data to stick around for a long time and most importantly you want to know it’s safe.
In the Docker world, there’s the maxim of “never patch”, always make a new container with the latest version of the application. If we’re sticking in our database in a container like Microsoft are doing with SQL Server now, what happens when we need to apply the latest patches?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failing my way to success with Azure</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/failing-my-way-to-success-with-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/failing-my-way-to-success-with-azure/</guid>
      <description>Experience my pain as I try to build an Azure Data Platform that scales.
Abstract Azure is a constantly evolving area, with more new features per day than I could shake a stick at. It’s awesome, you can use PowerShell, it’s cheaper than tin. It’s the future, so they tell me. It’s also a real PITA when you’re trying to achieve a task and you don’t know which bit is best!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get going with modern R in SQL Server in 30 minutes</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/microsoft-sql-server-and-r-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/microsoft-sql-server-and-r-services/</guid>
      <description> Learn about provisioning data science machines for production, programmatically.
Abstract Description Starting with provisioning a SQL Server on Azure, this end to end demo shows you how get everything set up to start using the best R packages available in realtime.
Slides View the presentation full screen or view it below. Hit the Space bar to navigate through the slides.
 Get more info in the repository
Videos  Presentation history  October 24th, 2016 - UK TechDays Online at Future Decoded October 24th, 2016 - SQL Bristol  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure for R peeps</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/infrastructure-for-rpeeps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/infrastructure-for-rpeeps/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s important to know how to work your operating systems &amp;ndash; if only so you know how to avoid working with your operating systems!
Abstract Continuous integration, Docker, openCPU, shiny server, RStudio server, Microsoft R Server, R in Hadoop, your laptop, your grid computer &amp;hellip; There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of infrastructure out there and someone has to configure it. This session whistle-stops through networking, Linux basics, and other key concepts to help get you up to speed because one day, the person configuring the server could be you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git in 5 minutes</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/git-in-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/git-in-5/</guid>
      <description> Learn about source control &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;ll save your bacon!
Abstract Git can seem scary but once you know a few key terms it&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy day to day. This lightning talk helps fasttrack you through the basics.
Slides View the presentation full screen or view it below. Hit the Space bar to navigate through the slides.
 Presentation history  July 27th, 2016 - SQL Guerilla talks  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My ways of being lazy with infrastructure</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/being-lazy-with-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/being-lazy-with-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description> Learn how we can take some of the effort out of infrastructure work
Abstract Oops, I never made one apparently!
Slides View the presentation full screen or view it below. Hit the Space bar to navigate through the slides.
 Presentation history  May 17th, 2016 - IT Pro Portugal  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>