<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sql Server on Locke Data Talks</title>
    <link>http://lockelife.com/talks/tags/sql-server/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sql Server on Locke Data Talks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lockelife.com/talks/tags/sql-server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R &amp; SQL Server for real-time predictions</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/r-and-sql-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/r-and-sql-server/</guid>
      <description>Putting data science models with SQL Server can be a great and simple way to operationalise your data science models. Learn how to do it.
Abstract Embedding your R (and soon Python!) models in SQL Server enables you to add predictive capabilities to your applications and analytics in place of buying expensive components or making substantial changes to your systems. In this demo-packed talk, you&amp;rsquo;ll see how you can go from a model built in R to making predictions on the fly in SQL Server 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anchor Modelling - agile databases</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/anchor-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/anchor-models/</guid>
      <description>Yes, there&amp;rsquo;s normal forms beyond third, and yes they can be really useful!
Abstract Anchor Modelling is a fantastic database modelling paradigm that uses sixth normal form (6NF) to store data and provides third normal form (3NF) views for ease of use.
This session deep dives into all the concepts behind Anchor Modelling (and indeed databases generally!) and then takes you through how Anchor Modelling uses these concepts to move away from the traditional data warehouse paradigm to deliver a purely additive, agile database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get going with modern R in SQL Server in 30 minutes</title>
      <link>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/microsoft-sql-server-and-r-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lockelife.com/talks/post/microsoft-sql-server-and-r-services/</guid>
      <description> Learn about provisioning data science machines for production, programmatically.
Abstract Description Starting with provisioning a SQL Server on Azure, this end to end demo shows you how get everything set up to start using the best R packages available in realtime.
Slides View the presentation full screen or view it below. Hit the Space bar to navigate through the slides.
 Get more info in the repository
Videos  Presentation history  October 24th, 2016 - UK TechDays Online at Future Decoded October 24th, 2016 - SQL Bristol  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>